<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reviews on </title>
    <link>/tags/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reviews on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Science content on YouTube</title>
      <link>/posts/reviews/2021-04-18-science-content-on-youtube/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reviews/2021-04-18-science-content-on-youtube/</guid>
      <description>Some of my favourite science content on YouTube
PBS Eons
Covers life on earth, including some great videos about early humans.
Veritasium
Pretty cool science channel, where he explains different science phenomena. Based on his philosophy (from his PhD work) that showing people misconceptions and then correcting them is what gets them to learn. Showing the &amp;ldquo;truth&amp;rdquo; directly leaves them with the feeling that their preconceived (often incorrect) notions were right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A little history of philosophy by Nigel Warburton</title>
      <link>/posts/reviews/2021-01-28-a-little-history-of-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reviews/2021-01-28-a-little-history-of-philosophy/</guid>
      <description>Overall rating: 9/10 Recommended if: you want to start reading about philosophy Level: Easy, intro-level.
Summary In short (heh), a great introduction, covering a lot of philosophers. I liked it better than whatever I&amp;rsquo;ve read of The Story of Philosophy. Sometimes I wonder if Nigel accidentally misrepresented/misfocused what philosophers stood for to ensure transitions between chapters were smooth (for eg:- I&amp;rsquo;ve seen Locke contrasted with Hobbes in the past, but could draw no such contrast here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear circuits</title>
      <link>/posts/reviews/2015-04-05-linear-circuits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reviews/2015-04-05-linear-circuits/</guid>
      <description>Link to course
University: Georgia Institute of Technology
Overall rating: 4/5
Recommended if: You want to know what would be taught in your first circuits course in college or are just interested in refreshing what you learned about circuits.
Level: Intro
Good: Covers and explains the basics in an easy to understand manner. Discussion forums were helpful. Lots of numerical problems to ensure you understand a decent amount.
Bad: Some topics are glossed over - like transformers and the wheatstone bridge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dino 101</title>
      <link>/posts/reviews/2015-03-16-dino-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 23:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reviews/2015-03-16-dino-101/</guid>
      <description>Link to course
University: University of Alberta
Overall rating: 4/5
Recommended if: You are mildly interested in dinosaurs, evolution or animals. Also, if you would like to know what paleontologists do.
Level: Intro
Good: A great intro to dinosaurs and paleontology. The instructors take feedback seriously and have changed the course since the first offering.
Bad: Wish it went into more detail and was more challenging. It felt like a course without a lot of college level content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning how to Learn</title>
      <link>/posts/reviews/2015-03-08-learning-how-to-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2015 12:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/reviews/2015-03-08-learning-how-to-learn/</guid>
      <description>Link to course (Now self-paced)
University: UCSD
Overall rating: 2/5
Recommended if: you like self-help.
Level: Easier than an intro
Good: Organized, has a structure.
Bad: Nothing that can&amp;rsquo;t be learned by browsing the web while procrastinating.
Interaction with other students: (3/5) Fair amount of discussion on the forums.
Work assigned: (1/5) Just some written assignments. Don&amp;rsquo;t feel like it really helped you learn the content (oddly enough).
Lectures: (2/5) A bit like watching a documentary, except a little more academic.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
