<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>technical on </title>
    <link>/tags/technical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in technical on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/technical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A guide to code reviews - reviewed!</title>
      <link>/posts/technical/2021-03-24-a-guide-to-code-reviews-reviewed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technical/2021-03-24-a-guide-to-code-reviews-reviewed/</guid>
      <description>Over my career as a software developer, I&amp;rsquo;ve changed how I approach code reviews. Simply put, I think of code in more practical terms and less as an &amp;ldquo;art&amp;rdquo;. Concepts of beauty, and perfection are best left to be incrementally achieved, and should always be considered with the end goal in mind (delivering value to the customer). Below, I&amp;rsquo;ve included my post from 3 years ago, with edits.
This here is a collection of things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about reviewing code in the few years that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked as a software developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about encryption - again!</title>
      <link>/posts/technical/security/2018-11-05-lets-talk-about-encryption-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 23:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technical/security/2018-11-05-lets-talk-about-encryption-again/</guid>
      <description>This post is part of a multi-part series.
For part 1, click here.
Wolf Einstein The wolf has realized you&amp;rsquo;ve foiled his initial plans, and he&amp;rsquo;s decided to up his game. Now, he knows you encrypt your message with your private key. He decides he will decrypt the message with your public key, which will let him know exactly when you plan to visit. THen, he plans to intercept you on the way to your grandmother&amp;rsquo;s house - just like the fairytale foretold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about encryption</title>
      <link>/posts/technical/security/2018-11-05-lets-talk-about-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 23:51:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technical/security/2018-11-05-lets-talk-about-encryption/</guid>
      <description>The better to write you with Let&amp;rsquo;s say you are Red Riding Hood, and you want to write a letter to your grandmother telling her you will be visiting. However, the big bad wolf is aware of your plans, and he decides he will also write a letter to your grandmother (pretending to be you) saying you won&amp;rsquo;t be visiting. If only there was a way you could let your grandmother know your letter was from you and the wolf&amp;rsquo;s letter was a fake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to code reviews</title>
      <link>/posts/technical/2018-01-29-a-guide-to-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technical/2018-01-29-a-guide-to-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>This here is a collection of things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about reviewing code in the few years that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked as a software developer. As these are my thoughts, you should take them with at least a pinch of salt instead of at face value, as with most subjective things in life.
When I first started, I reviewed code very differently from how I review code now. Despite this being a very important skill, it is not taught in high school or even college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>H*cking around</title>
      <link>/posts/technical/security/2017-09-23-hacking-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 22:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technical/security/2017-09-23-hacking-around/</guid>
      <description>Intro People think hacking requires a great deal of skill (on the part of the attacker) and/or a great deal of skill (on the part of the defender). This is quite clearly false. There are many simple ways to exploit a system. In this post, I detail some of the times I got access to accounts I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been able to get access to. While these are not the specific ways that a system&amp;rsquo;s bugs are taken advantage of, in general the principles hold true.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2FA, phishing and U2F</title>
      <link>/posts/technical/security/2017-09-06-2fa-phishing-and-yubikey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2017 23:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technical/security/2017-09-06-2fa-phishing-and-yubikey/</guid>
      <description>Intro As part of efforts to improve security, my workplace has issued us Yubikeys. What is a Yubikey? It&amp;rsquo;s a device you plug into your computer&amp;rsquo;s USB port and when you touch it for a few seconds, it spits out a string. This string is used for authentication (to identify you). The device has a capacitive sensor to detect touch, just like most phones today (old phones that used a &amp;ldquo;stylus&amp;rdquo; use resistive-touch based on resistors).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
