<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>activities on </title>
    <link>/tags/activities/</link>
    <description>Recent content in activities on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/activities/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>March review</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2021-03-31-march-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2021-03-31-march-review/</guid>
      <description>Habit goals  10 minutes of walking per day. [Same as Feb]. Third month in a row. 2 times a week running (for varying times). [Slight change from Feb]. Tracking 2 5Ks a week. 3 chess puzzles in a row every day. [Changed from Feb]. 1 chess blitz game (3+2) per day. Play &amp;amp; analyze. 3 sets of push-ups every other day. [Same as Feb] Weighted, 3x11 with 2:00 rest between sets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>February review</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2021-02-28-february-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2021-02-28-february-review/</guid>
      <description>Started the February &amp;ldquo;review&amp;rdquo; a bit early this time, stated my goals, and tracked them more regularly (aiming for every week). I think this gives me a good chance to pivot on goals as necessary.
Habit goals  22 minutes of reading every day. [Drop from Jan] Down from 30 minutes in January, which was a little too much for me. Again, counting only time spent reading books, not articles. Modified to read 1 chapter (of DDIA) per day on Feb 13.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January review</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2021-01-31-january-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2021-01-31-january-review/</guid>
      <description>After seeing others (Susan Fowler, Julia Evans, etc.) write year-in-review posts, I thought I should give it a go too! However, I don&amp;rsquo;t trust my discipline to last all year. So, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to post monthly reviews.
For January, I set the following goals, all framed in a &amp;lsquo;habit&amp;rsquo; style.
 30 minutes of reading every day. Reading was a fond childhood habit, which I have replaced with oodles of pointless Redditing, YouTubing and Twittering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of flights and men</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2018-12-20-of-flights-and-men/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 23:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2018-12-20-of-flights-and-men/</guid>
      <description>“Woah!” he chortled.
“I look different, I guess.”
“You look like a writer.”
I hadn’t seen Ashish for quite some time. We went to the same school, but only struck up a friendship towards the end of high school. We lived awfully close (less than a km away from each other), but it was only by the eleventh grade that my parents deemed I could walk a kilometer safely by myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to charity</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2018-09-18-a-guide-to-charity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2018-09-18-a-guide-to-charity/</guid>
      <description>Intro I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a few thoughts about charity floating around in my head. This post is a way for me to record some of those thoughts.
Deciding where to give For me, this has been the most important question when donating any money/time/effort. If you have X dollars to donate, where should you donate this money?
Goal 1: Effective allocation No one wants to see their money wasted. The primary concerns I had were that the money would not be used appropriately (either the charity is a front for a scam, or just inefficient in the way it utilizes funds).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Outlook</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2018-04-11-optimizing-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 19:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2018-04-11-optimizing-outlook/</guid>
      <description>Introduction They say &amp;ldquo;necessity is the mother of invention&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible the power programming gives you. Maybe if the power-hungry learned how to program they could be constructive rather than destructive. Then again, the recent Facebook scandal makes you wonder.
The problem Stepping down a few rungs and we&amp;rsquo;re back to the little world I live in. For the past few days/weeks, I had been frustrated by the lack of mailbox space at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A rating system for table tennis</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2018-03-12-a-rating-system-for-table-tennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Mar 2018 17:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2018-03-12-a-rating-system-for-table-tennis/</guid>
      <description>Background At work, during breaks, most of my team plays table-tennis. This weekend, I decided to spend some time writing up a rating system that I could use to keep track of how good (or bad) I (and everyone else) was. This is a writeup of how that exercise went. I&amp;rsquo;ve hidden a few lines to act as spoiler (indicated by an arrowhead to the left of the line). If you wish to exercise your mathematical skills, try making a guess and then click the line to reveal how I solved the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The quiz-biz</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2018-02-07-quiz-biz/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 23:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2018-02-07-quiz-biz/</guid>
      <description>Intro For a large part of my life, from when I was about 10 years old till I left college, I used to take part in quizzing competitions. A couple of times, I&amp;rsquo;ve had people ask me how they could start quizzing, or what preparing for a quiz would entail. This is a question I have some difficulty answering, because I have never really prepared for a quiz. In fact, procrastinating while trying to prepare is pretty much how I learned some of the different tidbits that have helped me win different quizzing competitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to code reviews</title>
      <link>/posts/technical/2018-01-29-a-guide-to-code-reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 01:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/technical/2018-01-29-a-guide-to-code-reviews/</guid>
      <description>This here is a collection of things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned about reviewing code in the few years that I&amp;rsquo;ve worked as a software developer. As these are my thoughts, you should take them with at least a pinch of salt instead of at face value, as with most subjective things in life.
When I first started, I reviewed code very differently from how I review code now. Despite this being a very important skill, it is not taught in high school or even college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My weird walk to work</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2017-10-10-my-weird-walk-to-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 19:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2017-10-10-my-weird-walk-to-work/</guid>
      <description>The walk Intro I&amp;rsquo;m sure a few other people do, or try to do this, so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how unusual it is, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d post about it regardless. I walk to work. Almost everyday. And usually (like a good engineer ;) ), if I do something repeatedly, I try toptimize it. With code, with life. So, now that it&amp;rsquo;s been a few months of walking to work in Seattle, I think I can present my learnings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to finances</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2017-01-30-a-guide-to-finances/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 19:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2017-01-30-a-guide-to-finances/</guid>
      <description>Intro I write this article to provide an easy way for people just entering the workforce (many of my friends) to manage their finances. I also think this article would also be a good reference for me, and may prove interesting (in hindsight) in a few years. If you want to spend as little time as possible, skip to the end. I would appreciate comments if you find this useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probability and tennis</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2015-05-31-probability-and-tennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 18:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2015-05-31-probability-and-tennis/</guid>
      <description>The idea The other day, while surfing Reddit, I came across a few comments that said having a 55% chance of winning a point would give you a 99% chance of winning the game. I&amp;rsquo;d heard this before, but this time I thought, &amp;ldquo;Hey! I can simulate that and see if it makes sense.&amp;rdquo; Seemed a bit unrealistic to me, that 50% would mean dead-even whereas 55% would mean a blowout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First race</title>
      <link>/posts/activities/2015-05-12-first-race/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 22:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/activities/2015-05-12-first-race/</guid>
      <description>Ran my first race on May 2nd. A 20 km run around Lake Monona.
Started off too fast - too confident despite not having trained since the end of March. Soon, I was tired enough that I would end up walking not insignificant distances throughout the race. Even with all the walking and the pleasant weather, 20 km was really exhausting. Not sure if it&amp;rsquo;s a Wisconsin thing, but two pints of beer is what you get after you cross the finish line.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
