<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thoughts on </title>
    <link>/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thoughts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Ashwin Menon</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hard work catalog</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2022-12-24-hard-work-catalog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2022-12-24-hard-work-catalog/</guid>
      <description>Ongoing list of people talking about hard work, practice and preparation Rahul Dravid
at ~1:30 here. Also at 3:30 about being prepared. At 5:02 about practising in the nets (email to Pietersen). At 7:43 &amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t always control the results, but you can certainly control your preparation.&amp;rdquo; Kapil Dev at ~4:45 [here](https://youtu.be/9h-l_uBr7dE
Sunil Chhetri at ~5:00 here.
At 7:47 as well. Conan O&amp;rsquo;Brien at 4:04 here &amp;ldquo;If you work really hard and you&amp;rsquo;re kind, amazing things will happen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some predictions</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2022-11-20-some-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2022-11-20-some-predictions/</guid>
      <description>Ongoing list of predictions
Format: [Date], [chance of prediction coming true in my estimation]: [time period]
2022-11-20, 60%: Apple/Google will make a moderation decision on behalf of Twitter by banning it from the app/play store. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Some thoughts</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2022-10-31-some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2022-10-31-some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>In a stark departure from my usual posts, here is some utterly unscientific nonsense that I mull over from time to time:
You can convince people to believe you are great, if others simply keep repeating that you are. What&amp;rsquo;s even more surprising, is that you can even do this without the help of others. Simply praise yourself all day, everyday, and take credit for accomplishments that have involved great help from others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech interviews: beating the game</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2022-02-10-tech-interviews-beating-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2022-02-10-tech-interviews-beating-the-game/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer/Foreword: The aim of writing this series of posts is to allow our modern interview processes to be viewed through the lens of history (chronicling the process) and science (identifying problems and inferring improvements from process changes). This is part two in the series, which will focus on how to maximize your chances given the current state of the system. The rest of this post assumes you&amp;rsquo;ve read part 1, and are interested in interviewing for tech/big tech companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech interviews: an origin story</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2022-01-21-tech-interviews-an-origin-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2022-01-21-tech-interviews-an-origin-story/</guid>
      <description>Disclaimer/Foreword: The aim of writing this series of posts is to allow our modern interview processes to be viewed through the lens of history (chronicling the process) and science (identifying problems and inferring improvements from process changes). This series will contain 3 parts: the first one (this post) describes how interviews got to be the way they are today, the second will describe how you can maximize your chance of success at these interviews, and the third will talk about suggestions to improve the process and fix some of the issues plaguing tech interviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on my career</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2021-05-27-reflections-on-my-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2021-05-27-reflections-on-my-career/</guid>
      <description>Having worked for a little over six and a half years as a professional software engineer, now may be a good time to reflect on what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned and how I&amp;rsquo;ve grown.
Company 1 In my first role, I primarily worked on implementing bug fixes and small features. While I feel bug fixes are not well considered by the industry, I really enjoyed working on them. They work as great on-boarding tools, allowing developers to come in and simply implement the fix or can also be great tools for learning the code-base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about: Health Costs</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2019-10-21-lets-talk-about-health-costs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2019-10-21-lets-talk-about-health-costs/</guid>
      <description>Drug prices are similar to the points in &amp;ldquo;Whose Line is it Anyway?&amp;rdquo; - they&amp;rsquo;re made up. The price that is shown in the infographic (250$) is purely artificial, considering the drug maker gives a $62.50 rebate, meaning the actual cost to the drug maker is only $187.5.
Image from Kaiser Health News shared under a CC license.
Textual description What happens is, the company that makes the drug sets a price, let&amp;rsquo;s say 250$ (this is a &amp;ldquo;fake&amp;rdquo; price as you will see).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about: Climate Change</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2019-10-10-lets-talk-about-climate-change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 21:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2019-10-10-lets-talk-about-climate-change/</guid>
      <description>With all the recent news and coverage that climate change is getting, it is easy for one to get a sense of ennui, to develop a numbness to each new report that paints a grimmer version of the future compared to the previous one. It is easy to feel helpless, as if relying on the ability of a captain on a sinking ship. This post is written as an attempt to try and get you to disavow that notion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashwin helps an Olympic medalist</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2016-11-02-ashwin-helps-an-olympic-medalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2016-11-02-ashwin-helps-an-olympic-medalist/</guid>
      <description>Part 1 As an Indian watching the Olympics, there is not much to look forward to. The best in our one billion-strong nation don&amp;rsquo;t make it past the qualification criteria for most sports. And, when they do, they are usually found at the bottom of the standings - forming a solid base from which, every Olympics, we moan the dearth of infrastructure and the deluge of corruption in India.
The list of medals won per capita at the Summer Olympics has India finishing last in Total Medals per Capita, Gold Medals per Capita and second-to-last (woot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love, Drugs And Rock N&#39; Roll</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2016-08-22-love-drugs-and-rock-n-roll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2016 23:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2016-08-22-love-drugs-and-rock-n-roll/</guid>
      <description>[Disclaimer: I have no degrees in Psychology, Biology or Anthropology. I would love to receive comments, clarifications or corrections.]
Love I was never insane except upon occasions when my heart was touched
Edgar Allan Poe Love - a feeling succinctly defined by the Oxford dictionary as &amp;ldquo;an intense liking for another person&amp;rdquo;. An emotion intense enough to form the backdrop of literary and cinematic tragedies - Romeo and Juliet, Joel and Clementine and my personal favourite, Eloisa to Abelard*.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about: The Olympics (Match Sprint)</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2016-03-29-lets-talk-about-the-olympics-match-sprint/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2016-03-29-lets-talk-about-the-olympics-match-sprint/</guid>
      <description>Sprint: To race or move at full speed (Dictionary.com)
Given the above definition, it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t surprise you that the fastest cyclists in a match sprint reach speeds as high as 70 km/h. Watching the event may leave you confused - it looks like they are fighting to lose the race. The sprint shown below looks, at times, like a slow-cycling event:
What&amp;rsquo;s happening here is that being in second-place, right behind the leader, reduces drag (friction with the air) by quite a large amount - around 30%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s talk about: Dinosaurs</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2016-03-10-lets-talk-about-dinosaurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 02:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2016-03-10-lets-talk-about-dinosaurs/</guid>
      <description>Dinosaurs.
Intro - Archosaurs We begin the journey around 250 million years ago, at the end of the Permian era, marked by the largest mass extinction in Earth&amp;rsquo;s history. The Permian-Triassic extinction event was catastrophic, claiming around 90 percent of marine life and 70 percent of life on land. Synapsids, animals that dominated the Permian landscape, were all but wiped out. A few trickled through, biding their time to regain their kingdom in a later era, but for now what was important was that life had entered the Triassic era - albeit barely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The joy of tennis</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2015-10-02-the-joy-of-tennis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2015 03:08:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2015-10-02-the-joy-of-tennis/</guid>
      <description>Asterisks are explained at the bottom.
Intro Sports - activities where people try to prove they are better than others at an activity they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be caught dead doing otherwise. Outside the world of sports, it would be ludicrous to find 11 people running behind a ball, but say you can do it better than any other set of 11 people, and the world will throw millions at you. While they might seem stupid if you try thinking about the higher purpose in the purpose of sports, you would be hard pressed to find someone not tuning in for the big final.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First post</title>
      <link>/posts/thoughts/2015-03-05-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 19:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/thoughts/2015-03-05-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hi, and welcome to my blog.
Here, I will keep you up to date on the things I am working on. Hope you enjoy your stay.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
